A Guide to the Virginia Feminist Oral History Project, 2013-2014
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
The Virginia Feminist Oral History Project, 2013-2014
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
4.24 Gigabytes, 54 files, 24 folders (born-digital collection).
Shockley, Megan Taylor
Scope and Contents
The Virginia Feminist Oral History Project consists of oral history interviews that Dr. Megan Taylor Shockley conducted with women involved in second-wave feminism and related activism in Virginia during the late twentieth and early twenty-first centuries. Topics discussed in the oral histories include the interviewees' early lives and education; their experiences as feminists and activists; their work with various local, state, and national organizations; and their perspectives on feminism and the future of the movement. These oral histories document how the women interviewed understood their own progressive actions, how they formed their individual feminist perspectives on the world, how they related to other feminist women, and how they assess their work in light of the contemporary political landscape.
The collection materials include audio recordings and transcripts of the interviews. The interviewees include women active in a number of organizations, including the Virginia Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs, Richmond Lesbian Feminists, Lesbian Women of Color, League of Women Voters, National Organization for Women, Virginia Women's Political Caucus, and similar organizations, as well as professionals who work or have worked in anti-violence and pro-choice movements. The geographic span of the collection ranges from far western Iron Gate in Alleghany county to Virginia Beach, and from Northern Virginia to Draper in the Southwestern part of the state.
Access Restriction
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The materials in this collection were donated by the creators and Megan Taylor Shockley in 2016.
Alternative Form Available
Another version of this finding aid is available via the VCU Libraries Special Collections and Archives Finding Aids site.
Historical Information
The Virginia Feminist Oral History Project was created and conducted by Dr. Megan Taylor Shockley, a professor of history at Clemson University. Shockley collected the stories of second-wave feminists throughout the state with the intention of using them in written works on Virginia women's activism and feminism during the late twentieth and early twenty-first centuries.
The stories included in this collection serve to correct the historiographical record which tends to locate feminist activism only in Midwestern, Northeastern, and Western regions of the country by capturing the voices of a diverse array of women involved in different organizations and various aspects of the movement from a number of geographical regions across the state of Virginia. These oral histories also fill a gap in the written historical record by documenting the women's personal reflections and perspectives on how they became feminists, their relationships with other activists, and the relationships between women and various organizations that fought for women's rights.
Arrangement
Collection materials are arranged alphabetically by last name of interviewee.
Technical Requirements
The audio files are in mp3 format and accessible via any media player capable of playing this format.
Disclaimer
The content of oral history interviews is personal as it relies on the recollections and opinions of individuals as reported to the interviewer. The audio recording should be considered the primary source for each interview. Transcripts serve as a guide to the interview. As transcription is an interpretive process, transcripts may include errors and omissions.
Shockley, Megan Taylor; Virginia Equal Rights Amendment Ratification Council; League of Women Voters of Virginia; National Organization for Women
- Bonnie Atwood, 2014
  Scope and Contents
  Length: 2:09:20
- Lisa Beckman, 2014
  Length: 1:56:44
- Mary Bergeron, 2014
  Length: 1:55:21
- Lynn Bradford, 2014
  Length: 1:32:13
- Sandra Brandt, 2014
  Length: 1:52:42
- Betsy Brinson, 2013
  Length: 1:18:22
- Mary Dean Carter, 2013
  Length: 1:14:55
- Mary Coulling, 2014
  Length: 1:43:11
- Holly Farris, 2014
  Length: 2:05:03
- Georgia Fuller, 2014
  Length: 4:53:07
- Suzanne Keller, 2013
  2:01:37
- Denise Lee, 2014
  2:06:55
- Beth Marschak, 2013
  Length: 3:16:07
- Kate McCord, 2014
  Length: 1:39:53
- Emily McCoy, 2014
  Length: 2:46:45
- Sarah Payne, Melanie Payne-White, and Stephanie Tyree, 2014
  Length: 1:20:16
- Terrie Pendleton, 2014
  Length: 2:16:17
- Lee Perkins, 2014
  Length: 1:55:42
- Karen Raschke, 2014
  Length: 4:01:52
- Muriel Smith, 2014
  2:32:10
- Kristi Van Audenhove, 2014
  Length: 1:56:02
- Mary Wazlak, 2014
  Length: 1:50:50
- Bessida White, 2014
  Length: 2:25:12
- Boots Woodyard, 2014
  Length: 1:37:51